[theme music playing]
Nimfa!
[Camia] I don't know if I can
still trust you after this.
Miss Camia, I'm begging you!
Please, don't fire me.
[supporters] Diego, Diego!
You are the queen of hired killers
and hired rapists in this place!
Why would you even think
that Ivy would be supporting us
if she knew that I was the one
who tried to have her raped?
[Ivy] I'm only here to support my Arnaldo.
[Emilia] Didn't you tell me
Diego's party wouldn't make it?
[Nimfa] Don't worry, Ma'am Emilia.
I'm already working on it.
[screams]
One of our security personnel
is betraying us.
I want you to investigate,
and, if possible,
annihilate this creature
who calls himself "Jaguar."
[Raul] I'm going to your hideout
because Julio gave me an order
to annihilate every one of you.
[Rufo] Relax. All we need to do
is prepare for their arrival.
[loud explosion]
[Loring] Diego! This wasn't an accident.
They made it look like
the house caught fire,
but they took our money!
They took everything!
[Emilia] Through this, we will prove
if Ivy Aguas is Camia's backer.
[Raul] Papa. Looks like Jaguar
got ahead of us.
-Most of our men were killed.
-[Julio] What?!
[Emilia] I just got some information that
they're headed to Senator Magno,
so you have to set up an appointment
and beat them to it.
[Diego] Are you saying
Nimfa stole our funds?
[Nimfa] Are you suggesting I did this?
What if the Ardientes
really are using you?
I'm not their lapdog!
[Julio] You bastard! Jaguar, you bastard!
Find the families of all our
former men who betrayed us.
[Arnaldo] To our success.
To my fiancé.
To my future governor.
Come to think of it, hon.
It's like the universe
is telling us that you'll win,
and the other candidate won't be
so lucky during the campaign.
Well, everything that's been happening
is part of an intricate handiwork.
What do you mean?
Well, it's not my secret
to tell, hon. Sorry.
Honey. Hon!
I'm your fiancée, and soon to be…
Mrs. Torillo.
So, I think it's my right
to know everything.
Okay, sure.
Let's just say we anticipate
Diego's every move.
We just found out that
he'll be going to Magno…
for financial backing.
There's a spy…
in Diego's camp?
And are you saying that you had
Loring's house burned down?
Maybe yes, maybe no.
But one thing's for sure,
we're a political family.
And we have been doing this
for many years.
We're good at it.
No, actually, we're experts.
Okay? So if there's one thing
that I can assure you…
It doesn't matter who's up
against the Ardientes because…
we're gonna win.
Whatever it takes, we're gonna win.
[upbeat music playing]
[tense music playing]
-Ivy.
-Diego.
They burned down Aunt Loring's house.
Our campaign funding is gone, all of it.
But we'll come up with something.
We'll ask for help
from Senator Magno's party.
[suspenseful music playing]
Diego, I know what happened
to Mrs. Loring's house.
The Ardientes want to get
to Senator Magno first.
Especially now that they know
your funds are gone.
They know you'll ask help
from Senator Magno.
We'll plan our approach to their party.
I'll make sure they choose us.
Not the Ardientes.
[suspenseful music playing]
Hon?
Arnaldo!
Uh… Hon!
What are you doing there?
That's my office.
Well, uh… I was looking for you.
-Hmm?
-I was looking for you.
You were gone when I woke up.
Where'd you go?
Well… Morning run.
But why did you lock the door?
Oh, yes. Sorry, hon. Force of habit.
You see, after what happened
to Nanny Carlotta,
I'm afraid someone might come in
and kill me too.
So, I'm sorry if I locked the door.
Anyway, are you hungry?
I'll cook you breakfast.
-Yeah, I'm starving.
-Let's go.
Well, Camia.
How did you find out we were here?
Wow, how rude.
Well, what makes you think
that you're the only one
who thought of coming to Senator Magno?
Have you forgotten?
We used to belong to the same party.
It's only natural to ask for his help
regarding Arnaldo's candidacy.
Correct. We are here to strike a deal.
Some kind of a partnership.
Unlike you guys, I know you're
only here to ask for funds.
-Right?
-[Emilia] Mm-hm.
Didn't you leave Magno's political party?
You can no longer earn the trust
of the party you once took for granted.
And you've been stupid
and cowardly since we were kids.
I don't think there's
much difference now, okay?
So you have the right
to lecture us about politics
because you haven't proven yourself yet.
I'm grateful you didn't teach
me anything about politics.
Because if you had,
I'd be ashamed of myself.
You know, hon?
I think it's better if we
just ignore those peasants.
Right? Let's go.
-Great idea. Let's go.
-Excuse us.
[Arnaldo] Excuse me.
So, can we count on
the full support of your party?
There's a reason why we've
already parted ways.
What do you mean, Senator?
I guess it's better to leave
things as they are, Emilia.
And which candidate will you
accept into your party, Senator?
I would love to get to know
your other son better.
Well, excuse me, Senator,
but he's not my son,
and I cannot believe that you're
even considering that bastard.
Everything is still under consideration.
Well then, okay.
Thank you for
your time, Senator. Let's go.
If you think all I'll do is
shout at you through the phone,
then, you're wrong.
You worthless piece of trash!
Ma'am, how can I be worthless
when I sabotaged Diego's plans?
You're the worthless one
because up until now,
you haven't paid me yet!
If you don't pay me, I'll expose you!
Is that all you want?
Fine, stuff these down your throat!
Go, pick them up!
It's my turn
for some blackmail now. Come here.
[squeals]
[groans]
Do you know who you're dealing with?
You are dealing with Emilia Ardiente.
I can have you killed and make
it look like it was an accident!
Do you understand?! Come here!
I'm giving you until tonight
to finish your job.
Or else… Do you see that toilet?
That's the last thing
you'll see before you die,
you piece of shit!
[weeps]
Miss Ivy.
[tense music playing]
Oh, Ivy.
I thought you left with Arnaldo.
Why are you still here?
-I need to go.
-Are you okay?
I'm all right.
Nimfa.
[suspenseful music playing]
Here. Use these to wipe your face.
Thank you.
-I'm leaving too.
-Not so fast, Emilia.
You need to tell me
what that woman did to you.
I know we don't get along sometimes.
Is she hurting you? Just tell me if so
because I don't want anyone
to hurt my future mother-in-law.
And what makes you say that, Ivy?
You think that someone like me
would lose to that uncouth peasant?!
[scoffs]
You know, Ivy, I may have said
that her fashion sense sucks
and that I hate that she's Diego's ally,
but that's it.
Nothing more, and nothing less.
You know me, Ivy.
I love bullying people
with low self-esteem.
[both chuckle]
So that's why you can't bully me.
I'll go ahead.
Bye, future mother-in-law.
Bye, my daughter-in-law.
Aww.
Was it management…
the money…
or… the change of view, the environment?
Which of those things
I mentioned is the reason…
why you switched to Jaguar's side?
[stutters] I was just blinded,
Congressman.
I was forced to do it
because of my colleagues.
Besides, Jaguar has a lot of money.
His money's like water
in the ocean, it's endless!
Well…
Where is this fountain of wealth located?
At the old hideout.
[exhales sharply]
Where is this old hideout?
First, you have to promise me
that you'll really give me
that new house and land in Manila,
where my family and I can start anew.
Inside this envelope, you'll find the keys
to a brand new car…
and the title
to a house and lot in Manila.
You can check it.
You can even have it investigated.
Everything is under your name.
[Rufo] I'm sure Julio will get back at us.
Especially now that he knows
where our hideout is.
So? Are we supposed
to be afraid of him now?
No matter how many times he comes here…
he still won't be able to defeat
us. Because, first of all,
Julio Ardiente doesn't have enough men.
The Ardientes are powerless now.
They're weak.
So, now, it's time for you
to hold up your end of the deal.
Where can I find Jaguar?
At the old hideout in the town of Gulod.
-[suppressed gunshot]
-[grunts]
Idiot.
That's what you get for believing in me.
But now I know.
Jaguar's at his old hideout…
in the town of Gulod.
Give me those documents.
This bastard actually believed
I'd give him a house and lot.
Fool.
And clean up the mess he made.
Well, well, Mister Jaguar…
I guess I'll see you soon.
Yes, Senator. I'm not an Ardiente.
I was never treated like
an Ardiente by my own family.
And when I was a kid,
I saw just how
they treated my friend's family.
You killed my husband!
You killed him! Get out of here!
Mom, calm down.
[Ivy] Your mother, that rapist Raul,
the people who rule Poblacion Ardiente…
they had us slaughtered
like we were animals.
[Diego] I saw the struggles of all those
families who worked the fields.
You can't take away our land!
We won't back down!
[clamoring]
And, because of that,
I started to build my dream.
I promised myself that, one day,
a new government will rise.
There will be leaders who'll truly care
about the residents of Ardiente.
I'll admit that I still have a
lot to learn about politics.
And we chose your political party…
because we believe in you the most.
What if we believe in something
that goes against your principles?
I may be new to this…
but I'm not innocent.
I know that friendships
don't last in politics…
especially if two parties
no longer believe
in the same thing.
But as long as we help
each other out this election…
I have a feeling
that we'll get along well.
I'm lucky because you chose
to approach me.
Welcome to the party.
-Senator, thank you very much.
-My pleasure.
-Thank you.
-[Marlon] Thank you, Senator.
-Batch, Aunt Camia.
-Congratulations, Diego.
[suspenseful music playing]
-[gunfire]
-[grunts]
[gunfire]
-Jaguar! Jaguar!
-[gunfire]
-What's the matter?
-Jaguar, Julio's men are here.
[gunfire]
How did they find out where we are?
Some of the Ardientes' men
switched back to their side.
Jaguar, let's go.
No, we'll fight back.
[gunfire]
Jaguar!
You may have lured my people…
with your riches.
But do you know what the
greatest motivator in life is?
Fear!
Fear for your own life.
Fear for the lives of your loved ones.
[Julio] The fear of death.
Come with us.
Don't kill my family, Congressman!
-Don't kill them!
-Congressman, have mercy on us.
I'll join the group again, Congressman.
I'll do everything you ask, Congressman.
Just don't kill my family.
I'm fairly easy to talk to.
-[gunshot]
-My son!
Congressman! Don't kill my entire family!
It wasn't me. It was him.
[sobs]
[man] I'll go back to the group.
Just don't kill my entire family!
Congressman. I beg you, Congressman.
[woman yowls]
Jaguar! Come out!
I'm here!
Face me.
[gunfire]
Put your guns down. Now!
[tense music playing]
Hurry, come on!
-What happened?
-Here they come.
Folks…
I have good news.
Diego was chosen to be part
of the senator's party.
[cheers]
That's amazing! We finally have a backer.
Diego is finally in an electoral party.
Not only that, Auntie. We're
going to repair your house.
And Senator Magno promised us
our own headquarters too.
-That's great!
-That's great news!
We're so proud of you, Diego!
Thanks, Uncle.
I hope our partnership with
Senator Magno's party goes well.
-Boss, congrats.
-Thanks.
-Congratulations again, Diego.
-Thanks, Aunt Camia.
-Batch.
-Miss Camia, thank you.
-Congrats.
-[Camia] Excellent!
-Well, Batch won!
[indistinct lively chatter]
Raul, are you okay?
[groans]
-[Rufo] Jaguar…
-[Raul sighs]
[Natalie gasps]
What do we do? What should I do?
[groans]
This shouldn't have happened to me.
Soon enough, Emilia will know I'm Jaguar.
Open this.
Hurry!
Ouch! Careful.
Please don't die on me.
I'll do it! Just call the doctor!
Stupid Magno! He'll regret
that he didn't choose Arnaldo.
And if he chooses Diego instead,
I can kill him, Aunt Claire.
I can kill him!
Where's Papa?
Hey, can you relax, Mom?
There are many parties and donors
other than Magno's,
so just relax.
[Emilia sighs]
[tense music playing]
-Ma'am.
-Where should we deliver this?
I can take you there, ma'am.
Ma'am, this way.
Okay. Thanks.
[tense music playing]
[suspenseful music playing]
[goon] Congressman… is this all right?
Everything's set, Congressman.
-[door shuts]
-[suspenseful music]
Congressman.
I'll be right back.
Oh. Congressman…
I was just leaving the money in here.
Get those in order.
We're giving them away tomorrow.
Excuse me.
[Nimfa] What are you writing here?
[volunteer] The first one?
Those are the voters registered
in every precinct.
[Nimfa] I see.
[Marlon] Okay.
[phone ringing]
Hon. It's from Manila.
I have to take this.
-Okay.
-It's Joanne.
-Yes, Joanne?
-I'll just be here.
Let's have coffee.
Mom, what is it?
Lily, Senator Magno chose Diego!
That's great news!
Where is he? Let me talk to him.
He's not around…
But, Lily…
Thanks for helping out
with Diego's campaign.
None of this would've happened…
if it weren't for you.
Lily…
To be honest…
I want nothing more than
to be with you at this moment.
It would've been nice to celebrate…
our successes together.
But, I know that's not possible.
Not until we bring the Ardientes down.
We can't live like mother
and daughter yet…
so, Lily, I'll make do with
working with you from afar.
I miss you so much, Lily.
[quietly] Lily?
[tense music playing]
[phone ringing]
Excuse me. I have to take this call.
Nimfa, Nimfa, Nimfa.
What took you forever to call?
It's about time!
So… what will it be? Dead or alive?
Mom, could you look around you?
What? Why, dear?
See if there's anyone
keeping an eye on you.
I don't think so, dear. Why?
What's the problem?
I'm sorry, but I need to hang up now.
Do you have an update on Camia?
Nothing, Ma'am Emilia.
But I found out something more important.
[quietly] Mom.
Just now, someone called Emilia
while we were on the phone.
That's why the Ardientes are always
one step ahead of you and Diego…
because they planted a spy in your camp.
Yes, Camia does have a backer.
-Okay.
-But it's not Ivy Aguas.
Huh? What do you mean?
Then…
who is it?
Ivy Aguas…
is the only possible person
connected to Camia Cruz, right?
She's her only possible backer.
So, who is it? Tell me.
It's not Ivy Aguas.
It's Camia's daughter.
Lily Cruz!
-What?
-You heard me!
Lily Cruz is alive!
No. That's not true.
It can't be Lily Cruz. You are a liar.
How can she help Camia
if she's already dead?
She is dead as a doornail.
She can't be alive.
I'm sure of it. I heard Camia talking…
to Lily on the phone.
No. That is impossible.
Completely impossible!
[Camia] I knew it.
Emilia has a spy in our camp.
Mom, I need to hang up now.
I think Emilia's spy…
just discovered something.
I need to find out what it is.
All right, dear. Be careful.
I'll tell Diego about this. Bye.
[Nimfa] She's alive, Ma'am
Emilia. She must know…
what's happening for her to back Camia.
Lily Cruz is alive.
And it's possible she's here
in Poblacion Ardiente.
No! No!
[ominous music playing]
-Doc, thank you very much.
-He should be fine.
If something happens, just call me.
-Okay.
-Let's go, Doc.
Ouch! Hey!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry, I just…
Please don't pretend
like this is just a small bite.
One way or the other,
the Ardientes will find out
what you're really up to.
They'll catch you, and they will
crush you like a fly.
What do you want me to do?
I don't know. Well…
Maybe you can… stay here?
Let me take care of you?
Please?
[Claire] Emilia, what's wrong?
You look pale.
[suspenseful music playing]
Lily Cruz is alive, Aunt Claire.
She's Camia's backer. She's alive.
Lily Cruz is alive.
Lily Cruz? Camia's daughter?
That can't be.
That girl has been rotting
in her grave for 13 years now!
Yes. She is alive.
And she's helping Camia now.
She's her backer.
This is not happening!
-Do you have the child?
-[social worker] Yes, ma'am.
You know what to do. Finish her off.
[young Lily] Please let me go!
[gunshot]
She can't be alive, Aunt Claire!
She cannot be alive!
This isn't true.
Lily Cruz is dead! She's dead!
She's dead!
-Mom!
-Emilia!
-[Arnaldo] Water!
Get us some water!
Jaguar, while you're recovering,
I'll ask my boss for help.
You should. We lost a lot of men.
We need to get back at Julio.
My boss promised to send us more men.
People who can help us
gain more money and power.
Your boss can do that?
I need to meet him.
Jaguar, in due time.
Emilia! Emilia! Emilia!
-Mm?
-Emilia! Are you still alive?
You're a buzzkill, my girl.
Do you know I just got my men
back from the gambling den?
I should be celebrating right now.
But here I am in your room,
checking if you're still alive or dead.
I'm still alive, Papa. Alive and kicking.
Yes, I can see that now.
At least I can kill you myself.
What's this I'm hearing about?
The girl you had murdered
13 years ago is still alive?!
Is this Camia Cruz brouhaha
happening all over again?
Yes, Papa. Lily Cruz is alive.
How was I supposed to know
that girl had nine lives
just like her mother?
Emilia, you're this family's punch line.
I don't know how you live with yourself.
Papa, please.
I don't need your insults right now.
What I need from you is your support.
This might affect Arnaldo's candidacy.
Lily Cruz must be wiped off
the face of the earth!
I need you to help me
and support me, Papa. Please.
You are a hopeless case, my dear.
Nothing is impossible, Papa.
Well, come to think of it…
Nothing's impossible
with someone like you.
You know what you should do?
Go back to sleep.
You might have left your brain
in your dreams.
[young Lily wailing]
Mister, don't kill me!
-[gunshot]
-[loud scream]
Get up. Listen.
You have to get away from here. Go.
I've legally adopted you.
You'll be called Ivy Aguas.
They can't learn the truth about Lily.
They can't find out I am Lily.
I need to speed up my plans.
[phone ringing]
Hello, Ivy?
[Arnaldo] Ivy? [knocks on door]
Ivy? [knocks on door]
Hon?
-Are you okay?
-Hon?
Yes.
Shouldn't you be checking on your mom?
How is she, by the way?
Well, she's better than I expected.
Hon, I'm just curious.
What do you know about…
Lily Cruz?
What do you know about her?
Actually, not much.
The information just came from
Mom's mole in Diego's camp.
Your mother's spy? Who could that be?
I don't know.
The truth is, I'm not convinced
that this Lily Cruz…
is the one backing up Camia and Diego.
And why not?
Why should we be afraid
of someone who isn't here?
She's nothing but an abstract idea.
Mom and Camia are just being dramatic.
And this Lily Cruz and
Diego too. They're pathetic.
Hon, you should be careful.
The people you underestimate
will never underestimate you.
You never know,
it might cost us the election.
[scoffs]
I'm just saying.
[quietly] Lily Cruz.
Hello, Auntie?
Ivy called me, but then she hung up.
Have you talked to her?
Diego. Lily confirmed…
that Emilia planted a spy in our camp.
And there's only one person I suspect.
Is it Nimfa?
She's the only one close to us…
who's acting strange.
Diego, we need to investigate her.
Okay, Aunt Camia.
[Marlon] Batch, this house is huge.
It has three bedrooms.
-Oh. Miss Loring, Mister Pandoy.
-Yes?
You can stay here if you want to.
[Diego] He's right, Nanny, Uncle.
We should stay here for now.
We can't live in a burned house anyway.
You have a point. We'll stay
here so we can live together.
We might overstay our welcome, though.
We'll spend our time browsing
the Internet on this computer.
[chuckles]
-Mr. Pandoy.
-Yes?
You can browse the Internet?
Do you have that back on the farm?
Well, times have changed.
You have to adapt.
Wait, does this place have any Wi-Fi?
-[laughs]
-Yes, we do.
[Loring] Wi-Fi, you say?
You might become engrossed in it.
This is for office use only.
Anyway, Diego, can you make me an account?
-I want to use Facebook.
-[laughter]
-Look at her!
-Of course, Nanny.
[Camia] By the way, Diego…
Thank you.
You managed to enter a political party.
So, I'm pretty sure
you'll become the governor.
Thank you, Aunt Camia.
That's why we have to work
harder together in the campaign.
-Yes.
-Everyone, listen.
What are your suggestions
to improve Ardiente?
If you ask me, Diego…
I wish our town could have
a bigger hospital,
so the sick wouldn't have to travel far.
-He's right.
Hospital.
[Camia] To avoid what happened
to Nimfa's father.
-What?
-He was forced to leave…
to treat his sickness.
Nimfa, what was
your father's illness again?
-[Loring] What?
-Uh…
-I'm sorry?
-[Camia] Uh…
Didn't you say you needed money
because your father was sick?
Yes, ma'am. Um…
He has kidney problems.
-Why didn't we know about that?
-Fernan?
Hold on, Nimfa.
Where is your father staying, anyway?
[suspenseful music]
In Manila.
Well… He's staying at my aunt's.
Didn't I tell you that before?
[indistinct chatter]
Easy, guys. Easy.
[Marlon] You know, she's been
stressed out by her family.
Now, you're stressing her out too.
Let's just focus on our campaign, okay?
Who has any other suggestions
for our strategy?
How about you? Nothing?
[Claire] If we find out
who sent that check,
then we can trace her location.
Okay, Aunt Claire. Go ahead
and find Lily Cruz for me.
-Thank you.
-Okay.
-Eat your breakfast, okay?
-Thank you.
-[Claire] Hey.
-[Ivy] Hi, Mamita.
[smooches]
Emilia, how are you?
And what are you doing here?
If you're both here to laugh at me,
go ahead, have a laugh.
But, one day, I'll prove
to you guys that I'm right.
Lily Cruz is a threat
to our family and to this town.
For all I know, your spy
in Diego's camp is wrong.
How reliable is your intel, anyway?
If you're just here to
lecture me like Papa,
can you just leave?
-Hon, excuse me.
-Yes.
It's a good thing Arnaldo left,
so he won't have to hear this.
Emilia, you're so weak.
You're pathetic and a coward.
You know nothing about me, Ivy.
[chuckles] Do you want to go shopping?
Let's go shopping so that…
you'll forget that Lily Cruz.
So that you can move on.
I can't move on from Lily Cruz.
If I managed to get rid of her before,
I can do it again now.
Why do you even care?
Should Ivy Aguas be scared of
Lily Cruz?
[suspenseful music playing]
[chuckles]
I told you I'm not
scared of anything, remember?
Not even you.
Okay.
Speaking as your friend, if you want,
I can help you look for Lily Cruz.
Really? Do you actually think
I'd still believe you
after you maligned me
and the rest of the Ardientes?
You shouldn't vent your anger
on me, Emilia.
I am not Lily Cruz.
Then why are you so defensive?
And why can't you accept the fact
that ever since you arrived in this town,
my family has been having problems?
Hasn't your family always had them?
Your lives are made of problems.
Each and every one of you keeps
trying to bring each other down.
Emilia, you allow your dad to insult you.
You also believe anyone so easily.
I'll find Lily Cruz
no matter where she's hiding.
You need to mislead Emilia.
She can't discover your true identity.
We're going to hunt Lily Cruz.
[woman] Haven't you heard?
Emilia's nabbing all the women
who are the same age as Lily Cruz.
[Ivy] What will you do to them?
Where are you taking them?
[Emilia] I won't do anything
today that you won't like.
-Lily, dear.
-Mom!
Is Lily alive?! Where is she?!
-Yes! My daughter is alive!
-[Diego] Let go of her!
[theme music playing]